It has been roughly one century
since the Apollo moon landing.
（ナレーション）アポロが
月着陸を果たしてから ほぼ１世紀
Humanity's first exploration ship to Jupiter,
the Von Braun, is preparing to set sail,
人類初の木星往還船
フォン･ブラウン号が―
旅立とうとしていました
...carrying with it humanity's
hopes and dreams.
人類の夢と野心を乗せて
（ドアの開く音）
（一同の笑い声）
（課長）
国際放送だったんでしょう？
It was an international
broadcast, right?
（ラビィ）
そりゃ もう 月から地球まで―
You bet! It was on a network with 612
stations from the Earth to the moon!
世界 612局ネットですよ
（フィー）
ずるいよな ラビィだけ 放送 見て
That wasn't fair, watching it
by yourself like that, Lavie.
Relax, I made sure
to record it!
（ラビィ）
だから ちゃんと録画したじゃない
（課長）母ちゃんにも
見せてあげたいんだけど―
I want to show it to my wife, too.
Yu-chan, would you mind dubbing it for me later?
ユーちゃん
あとで ダビングしてくれないかな
（ユーリ）
オーグ形式でいいですか？
Is Ogg format all right?
（課長）そういうの分かんないから
任せるよ
I don't know anything about that stuff,
so I'll leave it up to you.
（アナウンサー）先日
モルニア軌道で発見された―
And now, a follow-up report on the mine
recently discovered in Molniya orbit.
機雷の続報です
連合は調査中として いまだ
コメントを拒否していますが―
INTO is refusing to comment at this time
because of the ongoing investigation,
機雷を回収したクルーの映像が
入ってきています
...but we do have footage that was taken
by the crew which retrieved the mine.
機雷を回収したクルーの映像が
入ってきています
（ラビィ）出るぞ 出るぞ
- Here I come, here I come!
Calm down, you've already
seen it.
（フィー）一度 見てんだろ？
（ＡＤ）どうして
そのデブリが―
How did you know that this piece
of debris was, in fact, a mine?
機雷だと
分かったんですか？
デブリ屋の勘ですよ
A debris hauler's
intuition.
長年 この仕事を
やっているとね―
When you work in this job long enough,
it just comes to you.
ピンと来るんです
（タナベ）
いきなり 大うそですね
You started off with
a big fib, huh?
（タナベ）
いきなり 大うそですね
（ＡＤ）
なるほど しかし―
I see. But you weren't afraid
of the mine?
営業トークって言ってよ
機雷を回収することに
恐れはなかったんですか？
Call it "putting a spin
on our business."
いえ 宇宙に浮かぶ
危険を取り除くのが―
Not at all. It's our job to remove all hazards
that are floating around in space.
我々の仕事ですから
よく言うよ
Laying it on kinda thick,
aren't you?
みんな見てるかー
お父さんは宇宙を守ったぞ
Are you watching, kids?
Your daddy kept space safe!
Khorana, Haal, Musharraf,
your daddy did it!
コラナ ハール ムシャラフ
お父さんはな…
- These are also the heroes
who saved ISPV-7...
（アナウンサー）彼らは 先日
宇宙防衛戦線のテロから―
（ラビィ）やったぞー！
（アナウンサー）彼らは 先日
宇宙防衛戦線のテロから―
...from the Earth Defense Front's
terrorist attack not long ago.
ISPV-７を守った英雄でもあります
フフフフフッ 英雄だって
In response to these heroic acts, words of
gratitude are coming in from...
Hear that? We're heroes.
Huh? They only showed Lavie.
あれ？
ラビィしか映ってないじゃん
It's because you used such strong language.
"Death merchants," and stuff like that.
過激なこと言うからですよ
死の商人とか
Yep. I was careful and made sure I didn't
violate any broadcast regulations when I talked.
そうそう 私はちゃーんと―
放送コードに引っ掛からないように
しゃべったからね
That's playing dirty...
きったねえの
Let's just say that it had
a good end result.
（ユーリ）
結果オーライとしましょう
この報道のおかげで―
After all, thanks to this report,
they can't disband Debris Section.
我々 デブリ課を―
解散させるわけには
いかなくなったわけだし
（ラビィ）そうそう
企業イメージって大事だから
That's right. Corporate image
is important.
Yeah, I guess.
（フィー）まあな
Still, it's hard to be happy about this, not when
we owe it to the likes of those people.
あの人たちのおかげっていうのが
素直に喜べませんけどね
We shouldn't complain. Now we
can all work together again.
いいじゃないの
また みんなで
働けるんだからさあ
あっ？
ハッちゃん
ほんとに辞めちゃったねえ
Ha-chan really did quit,
didn't he?
♪～
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
Phase 19
Endings Are Always...
Ladies and gentlemen, I am here at Lae,
Papua New Guinea's second largest city!
（リポーター）
皆さん 私は今―
パプアニューギニア
第２の都市―
ラエに来ています
奥に見えるのが木星往還船
フォン･ブラウン号の―
Behind me, you can see the #6 crew selection
testing site for the Jovian explorer Von Braun.
乗組員採用
第６試験会場です
There have been some 20,000 applicants!
応募総数は およそ２万
既に決まっているメンバーや―
Excluding the crew members and mission
specialists who have already been chosen,
ミッションスペシャリストを
除いて―
...a mere 18 will be ultimately be selected from this pool!
この中から最終的に選ばれるのは
たったの18人
That makes the odds a dizzying 1000-to-1 long shot!
倍率にして なんと
1,000倍以上の狭き門です
そして この試験に
チャレンジしてくれるのが―
And here to challenge this test
is Chevalier Serie,
女子テニス
元世界ランキング３位の―
formerly ranked #3 in the world in women's tennis!
セリエ･シュバリエちゃんです
- Hi, I'll give it my best! It's good to be here!
（セリエ）
はーい 頑張りまーす よろしく～
Yay!
イエーイ！
（ファンたち）イエーイ！
Check it out, it's Serie-chan!
（男性１）おい セリエちゃんだよ
What's your state of mind right now? You must be nervous.
Up close, she looks kinda huge.
（男性２）
近くで見ると 結構 大きいな
Well, she was #3 in the world, after all.
Still, she's really cute.
Let me think... Hm... I'd say that I'm feeling like I did the night before I won the Grand Slam!
そりゃ 世界３位だからな
でも やっぱ かわいいぜ
Maybe I'll become
a fan, too.
俺 ファンになっちゃお
（ハチマキ）
何だよ 緊張感ねえな
What's with these guys?
They sure aren't taking this seriously.
So I see!
まっ １次試験なんて こんなもんか
Well, this is only the first round of testing,
so I shouldn't be surprised.
（チェンシン）ハチマキ？
Hachimaki?
（ハチマキ）あ？
（チェンシン）ハチマキ
Hachimaki!
（ハチマキ）チェンシン！
Cheng-Shin?
そっか
社内公募で選ばれたのか やったな
You got picked as an in-house
applicant, huh? Way to go!
（ハチマキ）ありがとう
Thanks. I have to say, I was surprised.
You quit awfully suddenly.
それより驚いたよ
いきなり辞めるなんて
（ハチマキ）ああ
Yeah.
When I got back from the moon, they told me
you'd already gone down to Earth.
月から戻ったら
もう地球に降りたって聞かされてさ
何かあった？
Did something happen?
別に ただ…
Not really. I just...
（チェンシン）ん？
I just felt like it.
（ハチマキ）
ただ そうしたくなったんだ
When I heard that you'd quit, I was worried.
But I guess it was for the best.
（チェンシン）辞めたって
聞いたときは心配したけど―
よかったみたいだな
You've been sort of
gloomy lately, Hachi.
最近のハチ 何か暗かったから
When I made up my mind to get on board the
Von Braun, I suddenly felt better.
フォン･ブラウン号に
乗るって決めたら―
なんだか気が楽になってさ
Up until then, it was like I had
a huge weight on my shoulders.
それまでは なんか頭が重くってよ
あっ…
Do you think I shouldn't
have quit?
辞めなくていいのにって思うか？
いや ハチが決めたことだ
とやかく言わないよ
No. It was your choice to make.
I won't criticize you.
（ハチマキ）サンキュー
まっ もう辞めちまったわけだしな
Thanks. Anyway, it's too late
to do anything about it.
（チェンシン）でも―
You talked to Tanabe-san about it,
though, didn't you?
タナベさんには
ちゃんと話したんだろ？
（ハチマキ）あっ…
おい まさか 何も
言わなかったんじゃないだろうな
Hey, don't tell me that you
didn't tell her anything.
Sure I did.
She was the first one I told.
（ハチマキ）言ったよ
いちばん最初に言ったって
I see. You're keeping in touch
with her, right?
（チェンシン）
そうか ちゃんと連絡 取ってる？
（ハチマキ）あっ あ…
（チェンシン）してないのか？
You aren't?
You know that's not right.
そりゃ マズいだろ
いや だってさ
Well, I don't know what to
talk to her about now...
今更 何 話していいか
分からなくてさ
（タナベ）何も
辞めなくてもいいと思わない？
Don't you think it was stupid
to quit like that?
社内公募だってあったんだし
休職願 出すとか
There was that in-house candidate pool, so
he could've requested a leave of absence.
（リュシー）
で なんで辞めたんだって？
So, why did he say
he was quitting?
えっ？
聞いてみたんでしょ？ おむつ男に
You asked diaper man why,
didn't you?
（タナベ）うん
Yeah.
フォン･ブラウンの試験を受ける
I'm gonna take the Von Braun test.
So I can't stay here anymore.
だから ここにはいられない
（タナベ）
そんな せっかくみんなの気持ちが
ひとつになれたのに
You can't quit now, we're finally
pulling together as a team!
悪(わり)いな 今は
それしか考えられねえんだ
I'm sorry. But right now, I can't
have anything else on my mind...
Why don't you
just quit?
じゃあ やめちゃえば？
えっ 会社を？
The company?
No, not the company! I mean
give up on that stupid guy.
違うって
そんな男 やめちゃえばって
言ってるのよ
What it boils down to is that he chose
that spaceship over you, right?
要するに あんたより
宇宙船 選んだってことでしょう
そんなこと
That's not true!
In a situation like this, you're better off
focusing on the company instead of some guy.
（リュシー）この場合―
男より 会社 取ったほうが
いいに決まってんじゃない
でも…
But...
だって もし受かったら
７年も 行きっぱなしだよ
I mean, if he passes the test, he'll
be away for seven whole years.
遠距離恋愛にも程があるっての
Even long-distance relationships
have their limits.
But Cheng-Shin-san went down to try out too, didn't he?
（タナベ）
でも チェンシンさんだって
受けに行ったんでしょ？
Yeah... I've already given up
on him.
ああ もう諦めたから
え…
I can't waste my time
on an idiot like him.
（リュシー）あんなバカな男
相手にしてらんないわ
I want somebody who's
more stable.
私はもっと安定志向の人がいいの
タナベも考えたほうがいいわよ
You should give that some
serious thought, too, Tanabe.
How much was it?
（ハチマキ）いくらだった？
It's on me.
Call it a farewell present.
（チェンシン）
おごるよ せん別代わりだ
出すよ 俺だって お前には…
Gimme the check.
I owe you some dinners.
（チェンシン）いいって
こっちは ホテル代も会社持ちだし
Don't worry about it.
The company's covering my hotel bill.
（チェンシン）いいって
こっちは ホテル代も会社持ちだし
あっ…
（チェンシン）いいって
こっちは ホテル代も会社持ちだし
T-They are? Well, thanks.
そ… そっか 悪いな
…で どこのホテルなんだ？
So, which hotel
are you at?
（チェンシン）ゴールドクラウン
The Gold Crown.
Wow, pretty ritzy.
That's a world-class company for you.
（ハチマキ）
豪勢だな さすが一流企業
（チェンシン）ハチはどこに？
連絡先 教えといてくれよ
How about you, Hachi?
Give me your contact information.
（ハチマキ）えっ？ ああ
Um... Uh... Sorry,
I can't remember
the name of the hotel.
悪い ホテルの名前 忘れちまった
（ロックスミス）はじめまして
How do you do?
I'm Werner Locksmith.
ウェルナー･ロックスミスです
（ドルフ）ドルフ･アザリアです
I'm Dolf Azaria. Actually, this
is the fourth time we've met.
お会いするのは
４度目になりますが
（ロックスミス）ええ？
I used to be division director
of Second Division.
（ドルフ）
前は 第２事業部で事業部長を
（ロックスミス）ああ
システムも無駄がなかったし―
Ah, yes. Your system
ran like clockwork,
...and you could even provide me
with extra parts in just a day.
追加ファースも
１日でそろえてくれるとは
リサイクル施設の
余剰資源を回しました
I sent you some surplus material
from our recycling facility.
品質に問題はなかったはずですが
There were no quality control
issues with them, I take it?
This is wonderful.
（ロックスミス）
いやあ すばらしい
たかが弾よけ会社に―
I'm amazed that they sent a talented man
like yourself to run a mere cover company.
テクノーラが よくこんな
優秀な人材を出したもんだ
Unless... You were too talented?
ひょっとして
フーン… 優秀すぎた？
（ドルフ）んん…
What're you doing
out here?
（警察官）
こんな所で何をしている？
（ハチマキ）
見りゃ 分かるだろ？ 野宿だよ
What's it look like? I'm camping out.
（警察官）旅行者か？
You a tourist?
（ハチマキ）フォン･ブラウン号の
試験を受けに来た
I'm here to take the test
for the Von Braun.
This is Metro PD
unit 311...
（警察官）なぜ 宿を取らん
Why aren't you staying
in a hotel?!
（ハチマキ）
１次試験は 半月近くかかるんだ
The preliminary test is gonna
take nearly two weeks.
I can't afford to live out of
a hotel for that long.
そんなにホテル暮らしできる
身分じゃない
（警察官）ちょっと離れれば
安アパートは いくらでもあるぞ
There are plenty of cheap apartments
if you're willing to walk a bit.
（ハチマキ）
無職の人間には貸さないってさ
They say they won't rent to a guy
who doesn't have a job.
You're unemployed, huh?
All right, get up.
（警察官）無職か… もういいぞ
（ハチマキ）無職で悪いかよ
What's wrong with
being unemployed?
（警察官）
悪くはないさ だが よくもない
Nothing. But it's not good, either.
If you're going to camp out,
go to the Lagash district.
野宿なら ラガス地区に行け
あそこはホームレスのたまり場だ
That's a homeless hangout.
ホームレス
Homeless?!
What was that jerk Hachimaki thinking?
（キース）
ハチマキのやつ 何 考えてんだ
せっかく
送別会まで用意してやったのに
After all the trouble we went through
to put together a farewell party for him...
（ババイヤン）
バカなんだよ 結局
I guess he's just an idiot. He didn't have
to quit the company to take that test.
会社 辞めてまで
やることじゃねえだろ
（トモルド）
18人しか受からねえんだ
Only 18 people are gonna be selected.
It's damn near hopeless.
無理だよな
（バクティ）
万馬券 買うほうがよっぽど確実
He's got a way better chance of winning
betting on a dark horse at the races!
And with his academic background,
he isn't cut out for any other work.
（キース）あいつの学歴じゃ
潰し利かないしな
どうする 連絡取っとく？
What do you wanna do?
Wanna call him?
（トモルド）ハハッ まさか
As if!
皆さん おはようございます
Ladies and gentlemen, good morning.
I'm Dolf Azaria of Galileo Development.
ガリレオ開発の
ドルフ･アザリアです
我が社は 連合より―
We have been entrusted by INTO with the
management and operation of the Von Braun.
フォン･ブラウン号の
管理 運営を任されております
よって 乗組員選抜試験も
我が社が担当します
As such, we will also be overseeing
the crew selection testing process.
The division director was
transferred here, huh?
よって 乗組員選抜試験も
我が社が担当します
事業部長
こっちに回されてたんだ
For the next two weeks, we will put all of
you gathered here at the #6 testing site...
事業部長
こっちに回されてたんだ
ここ 第６試験場に
お集まりの皆さんには―
これより２週間
１次試験として―
...through our first round of testing, which will include...
基礎体力測定や
筆記試験を受けていただきます
...physical fitness assessments,
as well as written tests.
The details of the tests are on a separate sheet
in your test guide, so please look it over...
参照の上…
（ハチマキ）チェンシン
基礎体力の測定に行くんだろ？
Cheng-Shin! You're heading over to get
your basic fitness assessment, right?
I need to get
checked out, too.
俺も とっとと測っておかないと
（チェンシン）あっ…
Um... Actually, we're exempt
from the basic tests.
その…
僕ら 基礎試験は免除されてるんだ
えっ… ああ
（テクノーラ社員）
俺たちはシード選手
We're seeded players.
つまり予選はスルーして
１次の最終試験のみなんだよ
In other words, we get a bye for the
preliminaries, and only take the final test.
行くぞ テクノーラの広報が来てる
（チェンシン）はい
Let's go. Technora's PR people
are here.
Yes, sir.
大丈夫 基礎試験くらい
ハチなら楽勝だって
You'll do fine. A guy like you will ace
the basic tests, Hachi.
ああ
Sure.
Cheng-Shin!
（テクノーラ社員）チェンシン
はい
Coming!
タナベさんに ちゃんと電話しろよ
Make sure you call Tanabe-san,
you hear?
あいつか 半課にいたやつって
救えねえな
Is that the guy you mentioned?
The one from Half Section?
Looks pretty hopeless
to me.
No, he seems to have made the decision after
thinking it over carefully in his own way.
（チェンシン）いや 彼は彼なりに
考えて決めたことみたいですし
くっ…
（ホイッスル）
（ハチマキ）ハッ ハッ ハッ…
♪～
はい
Here.
（受験者）ふんっ！
Do you have
a minute?
（ハワード）ちょっといいかな
（ハチマキ）ん？
Why do you want to get
onto the Von Braun?
（ハワード）
なぜ フォン･ブラウン号に志願を？
Applicants 540 through 580 who
are in the Class CW program,
（ハチマキ）あ？
I'm sorry. The name's Howard. Bruder Communications.
（ハワード）
失礼 ブルーダー通信の
ハワードと言います
ご存じですか？
Were you aware that if the Jupiter project's
budget had been spent on them,
...make sure you complete your examination
check after entering the test site.
木星計画の予算があれば―
...40% of the people who starved to death
last year could have been saved?
昨年 餓死した人の
４割が救えたって
地球のことすら
ちゃんとできない人類が―
Does humanity really need
to try to get to Jupiter...
The third round of endurance testing
will now begin.
木星を目指す必要が
あるんでしょうか？
...when they can't even take care
of themselves here on Earth?
Applicants who beat their time in the previous
test by two minutes, please gather at Section E.
どう お考えですか？
What's your opinion
on that?
２号エンジンの事故で
何人 亡くなったかご存じですか？
Do you know how many people were killed
in the explosion of the #2 engine?
犠牲者のことは考えないんですか？
Don't you consider the
cost in human lives?
一方的なわがままだけで―
Do you think it's right for a few people
to drag along the whole human race...
人類をしょって立つような
振る舞いをどう思いますか？
...when all they're really thinking about
is themselves?
ねえ あんた！
Hey! I'm talking
to you!
Hell, I used to have nearly 20 people
workin' for me in the old days...
（男性１）俺だってな
昔は 20人近い部下をまとめてた
おっと…
Oops...
おっさん 大丈夫か？
You okay,
old man?
ヘヘッ
あんちゃん チャイニーズか？
Hey, buddy... You Chinese?
日本人だよ
I'm Japanese.
You know Tanaka over
at Sunset Lights?
（男性１）
じゃあ サンセットライツの―
タナカってやつ知らないか？
The Tanaka who used
to work for me.
俺の部下だったタナカ
知らねえな
Sorry, no.
タナカの野郎
The instant I quit the firm, that bastard
Tanaka's attitude did a 180...
俺が会社を辞めた途端
手のひら 返しやがってよ
You snuck off with
all my clients!
俺の客
ごっそり持っていきやがって
Hey, cut it out!
（ハチマキ）おい やめろよ
I taught you all you know about the job
and about the ladies, didn't I?
（男性１）仕事だって女だって
俺が教えてやったんだろう 返せよ
Give 'em back!
Damn it, I'm not Tanaka!
（ハチマキ）俺は違うって
You said that now that I wasn't your boss,
I was just another old man!
（男性１）上司じゃないあんたは
ただのおやじだってよ
若造が この！
You little punk!
しつこいぞ
（男性１）ああっ
Give it a rest!
What did ya do that for,
ya damn Japanese?
何しやがる 日本人め！
（男性２）えっ 日本人？
A Japanese?
（男性３）
ヘヘッ 侍 侍 ヘヘへッ
Samurai! Samurai!
ヘヘッ 侍 ヘヘへッ…
Samurai!
I bet he's got money
on him!
（男性４）
金 持ってんだろ？ おい ええ？
（男性５）
日本人がそっちへ行ったぞ
The Japanese guy
went that way!
（ハチマキ）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（荒い息）
（ハチマキ）あっ… あっ
待てよ 強盗とかじゃない
Wait a minute! I'm not a mugger!
（男性）星野(ほしの)か？
Hoshino?
えっ！？
（ハキム）ハァ…
（ハチマキ）ハキム
Hakim?
（ハキム）やはり星野か
I thought that was you, Hoshino.
You're here for the Von Braun testing, too?
君も フォン･ブラウン号の
テストを受けに？
（ハチマキ）あんたも？
（ハキム）ああ
You, too?
Yeah.
（ハチマキ）しかし こんな夜中に
What're you going out here
at this hour?
（ハキム）昼間じゃ
無駄に体力を使うだけだしな
If I ran during the day,
I'd only be wasting my strength.
（ハチマキ）
でも ジムを借りるとか
Couldn't you join a gym
or something?
They said that the don't let unemployed
people become members.
（ハキム）無職の人間は
会員になれないってさ
あっ… そうか 俺もそうなんだよ
You, too?
The same thing happened to me.
そうなんだよなあ
Don't even
get me started.
保険なくなるし
銀行とかも 金 貸してくれないし
You lose your insurance, and banks
won't lend you any money.
無職だからって…
Just 'cause I'm unemployed
doesn't mean...
Hey, what happened
with the OSA?
あれ？ 軌道保安庁は…
（ハキム）辞めたよ
I quit.
（ハチマキ）どうして？
How come?
（ハキム）保険を掛けて
追える目標ではないだろ？
The Jovian explorer isn't a goal you can reach
if you know you have a safety net.
あっ…
（ハキム）木星往還船は…
（タナベ）すみません
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have called you when
you're in the middle of such an important test.
大事な試験の最中に
わざわざ電話していただいて
（チェンシン）
気にしなくていいさ これぐらい
Don't worry about it.
It's no big deal.
そんなことより やっぱり？
So, is this what I think
it's about?
Yes, Hachimaki-senpai didn't tell me
where I could reach him, either.
（タナベ）ええ ハチマキ先輩
連絡先も教えてくれなくて
That jerk... I told him
to call you.
（チェンシン）
あいつ 電話しろって言ったのに…
ハチには よく言っておくよ
I'll tell Hachi the next time I see him.
He stole you from me, after all.
僕から奪ったんだからね
しっかりつかまえとけって
I'll tell him that he'd better
hold on tight to you.
あっ…
ハァ… どうすっかな
Man, what am I
gonna do?
（チェンシン）おはよう
Good morning.
ああ 今日のは免除じゃないのか？
Hey. You're not exempt
from today's tests?
Tanabe Ai
（チェンシン）
うん １次の最終試験だからね
No. This is the final test
of the first round.
電話 タナベさんに？
Were you about
to call Tanabe-san?
（ハチマキ）
あっ ああ… でも あとでいいや
Um... Yeah, but it can wait
until afterwards.
（チェンシン）どうして？
Why wait? I talked to her last night,
and she was really worried about you.
ゆうべ話したけど
彼女 心配してたぞ
（ハチマキ）
いや 最終試験 終わってから なっ
No, I'll call her after
the final test is over.
きっとだぞ
You better!
（ハチマキ）分かったって
Relax, I will.
ともかく 今は
中途半端なことしてられないし
Anyway, I can't split my
attention right now.
さあ いよいよ１次の最終試験です
Now, then, we're finally down to the
final test of the preliminary round.
シチュエーションは
至ってシンプル
The situation is
extremely simple.
木星軌道上 エウロパ周辺にて―
The Von Braun's life support system has
gone offline while in Jupiter orbit near Europa.
フォン･ブラウン号の
生命維持システムが停止
諸君は船外活動により―
You must go EVA and restore those
systems within ten minutes. This is...
10分以内に
システムを回復させねばならない
これは… ん？ ああ 君たち
Oh. Gentlemen?
We won't be needing you.
君たちはいいから
But a diver has
to accompany...
（ダイバー）
しかし ダイバーの追加が…
（ロックスミス）木星へ行ったら
ダイバーなんていないだろ？
There won't be any safety divers
when they go to Jupiter.
（ダイバー）それは…
Yes, but...
What if there's
an accident?
（受験者）
事故が起きたら どうするんだ
I don't need anyone on my team
who would die on Earth.
（ロックスミス）
地球で死んじゃうような人なら
要らないよ
木星でも死なない人が
欲しいんだから
You see, I want the kind of people
who won't die at Jupiter, either.
（受験者）ふざけるな！
あんた また殺す気か？
Are you kidding?! Are you trying
to kill even more people?!
無理に残ってくれとは言わないよ
お帰りはご自由に
I won't force you to stay if you don't want to
be here. Feel free to leave whenever you like.
（受験者）冗談じゃない
To hell with this! No way am I gonna
risk my life over some stupid test!
こんなことに
命 懸けられるかってんだ
（ロックスミス）
他の人も 怖かったら―
If anyone else is afraid,
feel free to quit if you like.
やめてくれて構わないですよ
相手は木星ですから
We're going up against Jupiter,
after all.
あと 公平を期すため
シャッターは閉じさせてもらいます
Also, to keep the test impartial,
we will close the shutter.
タイムなどは
控室のモニターで確認してください
Please use the monitor in the waiting room
to check the times of the other applicants.
He lives up to his reputation
as a ruthless man, all right.
噂どおり とんでもない人だな
そうか？
（チェンシン）えっ？
You think so?
駄目なんじゃないかな
あれぐらいじゃないと
Maybe the test really needs
to be a little dangerous.
（ドルフ）ダイバーは
プールサイドで待機させますよ
I'll have the diver stand by
next to the pool.
I understand, Mr. President.
I was just trying to scare them a little.
分かってるよ 社長さん
ちょっと脅してみただけだよ
（ドルフ）ん？ うーん…
（セリエ）
ジャーン！ セクシーショット
Ta-dah! How's this
for a sexy shot?
なーんて
Just kidding!
実は今 私は 水中作業試験の
順番を待ってるんです
Actually, I'm waiting my turn to take
the underwater activity test.
プールを使うことで
宇宙のまね事をするんですね
I guess they're using this pool
to mimic conditions out in space.
操縦士だろうと ミッション
スペシャリストだろうと…
Whether you're a navigator or a mission
specialist, they make you take...
（チェンシン）
機雷回収のニュースのおかげで―
She told me that it's business
as usual for Debris Section...
デブリ課は今までどおりだってさ
...thanks to that mine recovery
piece on the news.
（ハチマキ）ああ
Oh...
ラビィさんの子供たちが
学校で人気者に…
And she says that Lavie-san's kids
are celebrities at school.
ラビィさんの子供たちが
学校で人気者に…
（終了音）
もう終わったのか？
（受験者１）誰だ？ あいつ
It's over already?
もう終わったのか？
（受験者１）誰だ？ あいつ
Who's that?
（受験者２）早(はえ)え
（受験者３）246番って 誰だよ
That was fast!
Who's #246?
（受験者４）新記録だな
（受験者５）まだ５分だってのに…
It's only been
five minutes!
（受験者６）まいった…
Aw, man...
I know we're not judged by who's fastest,
but with a time like that, geez...
（受験者７）早けりゃ
いいってもんじゃないけど―
このタイムは さすがにな
あっ…
ハキム
Hakim...
あれ？ この人
まさか軌道保安庁に…
Hey, isn't that the guy
from the OSA?
あれ？ この人
まさか軌道保安庁に…
（アナウンス）次の組です
Next group.
あれ？ この人
まさか軌道保安庁に…
24 776 1043 1303の方…
#24, #776, #1043, and #1303,
please gather on the test floor.
24 776 1043 1303の方…
うん？
来たか
I'm up!
同じ組になったな
Looks like we're in
the same group.
ああ
Yeah.
さあ いよいよ
私の出番がやってきましたよ
All right! It's finally
my turn to go!
Group 12, team B.
Vitals check complete.
（試験官）第12組 Ｅ班
バイタルチェック コンプリート
テストを開始します
Now beginning test.
（ハチマキ）くっ…
（試験官）テストを開始します
Begin test.
♪～
（セリエ）
んっ もう どうなってんのよ
Geez, what's wrong
with this thing?
（カメラマン）
大丈夫ですかね セリエちゃん
Think Serie-chan is
gonna do okay?
１次試験くらい通ってくれないと
番組にならないですよ
We won't have much of a show if she can't
even pass the preliminary round.
♪～
（セリエ）空気 空気が…
助けてよ うわあっ ねえ！
My air! My air's leaking! Help me!
Help!
（受験者）セリエちゃん！
おい試験官 助けろよ！
- Serie-chan!
Hey! Examiners! Go help her!
（ドルフ）ダイバーを… ん？
Send in the diver.
自力で復帰できるかどうかも
試験のうちだよ
Determining whether she can recover
on her own is part of the test.
空気残量は？
How's her remaining air?
（係員）
右のチューブが生きてますから―
Her right tank is still functioning,
so she's good for another 20 minutes.
20分はもちます
じゃ もう少し様子を見よう
Then let's wait a while and see
how things develop, shall we?
それより
1303番の資料を見せてくれる？
Could you show me
the data on #1303?
He must have noticed the accident,
but he's ignoring her.
彼 気付いてるはずなのに
無視してるよねえ
（ハチマキ）ああっ…
（チェンシン）いけない！
Oh, no!
試験官 救出に向かいます
救護班の用意を
Examiners, I'm going in to rescue her.
Have a rescue team standing by!
（ハチマキ）俺には これしかない
This is all I've got...
I don't have anything else...!
これしかないんだ！
ああ…
（終了音）
（受験者）うんっ
タイムアップって何だよ
やり直しだろ！
What do you mean, our time's up?!
We should get to take it again!
事故だったんだぞ
無効に決まってる
There was an accident!
This obviously doesn't count!
宇宙でも事故は起こる
（受験者）けど…
Accidents happen in space, too.
Yeah, but...
It was the very first
thing I said.
最初に言ったはずだよ
ここは木星圏で
生命維持システムが停止したって
I said that this is Jupiter space, and the
life support system has gone offline.
君が
システムを回復させなければ―
If you hadn't gotten the
system running again,
フォン･ブラウン号の乗組員は
全員 死んでいたんだ
...the Von Braun's entire crew
would be dead.
（セリエの泣き声）
クルー全員と１人の命
どちらが大事か分かるよね？
You understand that the lives of the entire crew are more important than a single crewman's life, don't you?
This is just a test!
（受験者）でもテストじゃないか
（ロックスミス）本番ならできた？
- And she could have done it
if this were the real thing?
まさかね
I find that unlikely.
私の船に必要なのは
ヒューマニストではなく―
I don't need humanists
on my ship.
チームにとっての被害を
最小限に抑えられるリアリストだ
What I need are realists who will keep
any losses to the team to a minimum.
リアリスト？
ただのエゴイストじゃねえか
Realists? That guy's nothing
but an egomaniac!
ええっ？
You hear me?!
エゴイスト結構
Egomaniacs are fine by me!
I'm an egomaniac, too.
私もエゴイストだ
（受験者１）
お前 どう？ 自信ある？
（受験者２）昨日の水中テストは
タイム ギリッギリでさ
I just barely made the time limit
on the underwater test yesterday.
（受験者３）
今日もセリエちゃん 来るかな
Think Serie-chan is gonna
come today?
（ハチマキ）あっ 何だよ
見ないのか？ 結果発表
What's up, you're not gonna watch
the selection announcement?
昨日の水中試験
途中棄権したんだぞ
I withdrew from the underwater
test yesterday halfway through.
広報がらみの仕事も終わったし
引き上げるさ
Besides, all my PR-related work is done,
so I'm calling it quits.
そうか 残念だな
You are? I'm sorry to hear that.
気にするなよ
Don't worry about it.
I expected to fail from the very beginning.
僕は
もともと落ちる予定だったんだし
えっ… それって
The applicants who passed the New Guinea
preliminary testing will now be announced.
えっ… それって
（アナウンスの音声）
But that means...
始まるぞ
It's starting.
あっ…
We ask that all applicants
take a seat and wait.
テクノーラの枠は ２人なんだ
Technora gets two slots
for their personnel.
枠って何だよ？
Slots? What do
you mean?
It'll be great publicity for Technora
if some of their employees...
テクノーラの社員が入ってれば
いい宣伝になるだろ
...are on board the first manned mission
to the Jovian system, right?
フォン･ブラウン号の建造には―
They're also supplying funds and technology
for the Von Braun's construction,
テクノーラが
資金も技術も提供してるから―
無理が利くんだよ
...so they can force
their way on board.
それでは発表します
And now, the applicants
who passed.
（チェンシン）
社内公募で選ばれたのは 25人
25 people were selected for the in-house
candidate pool. But seniority counts.
#23, Jiri Mah Zeagan.
だけど先輩が優先さ 会社だよな
It's a company,
after all.
#42, Theodore Morrison.
If you knew that,
why'd you come here?
（ハチマキ）
それが分かってて どうして？
（チェンシン）
２万人から18人 無理だよ
18 people out of 20,000. It's hopeless.
#96, Jeff Smith.
正直 僕の実力じゃ
まだ足りないしね
To tell you the truth, I don't think
I'm up to the challenge yet.
#102, Sahmura Bandian.
実際の勝負は
次の次くらいだと思う
I think I'll stand a good chance
for the mission after the next one.
でも そのときのために
慣れておきたかったし
But I thought I should get a feel for it
for when the time comes.
（ドルフ）
197番 ハリエット･アンデション
#197, Harriet Andersson.
246番 ハキム･アシュミート
#246, Hakim Ashmead.
よし！
Yes!
#276...
（ドルフ）276番…
何だよ お前も記念受験か
What, so you took the test
just to say you took it, huh?
えっ？
#308, Luo Yucheng.
（ハチマキ）変だと思ったんだ
I thought it was fishy, the way you were so
concerned about Tanabe and all that stuff.
タナベのこととか
いろいろ気ぃ遣って
#311, Fatima Rhada.
遊び気分で見物か！
You just came here for fun
like you were sightseeing?!
だったら
余計な ちゃちゃ入れんな！
If you did, don't gimme any
of your damn pep talks!
俺は お前と違って―
I'm not like you! Without the
Von Braun, I've got nothing!
フォン･ブラウン号じゃないと
駄目なんだよ
Hachi...
ハチ
お前は
フォン･ブラウンじゃなくても―
You can get by just fine without
the Von Braun, am I right?
いいんだろ？
定期便のパイロットでも
他の仕事でも
You can work as a shuttle pilot
or do anything else!
（チェンシン）違う 僕は…
No, I'm...
And you can have any
woman you want!
女だって誰でもいいんだ
だから タナベも
あっさり俺に譲った
That's why you handed Tanabe
off to me without a fight.
うっ… 何だって！
What did you say?
（ハチマキ）
お前は いつだってそうだよ
You've always been like that! You've already
got it all, so you're not attached to anything!
何でも持ってて だから執着しない
女でも金でも しがみつかなくても
いっぱい持ってるからな！
You can throw away money or women!
There's always more where they came from!
女でも金でも しがみつかなくても
いっぱい持ってるからな！
（ハキム）うん？
女でも金でも しがみつかなくても
いっぱい持ってるからな！
But I'm not like you!
It's the Von Braun or nothing!
俺は違う！
俺は フォン･ブラウンだけだ
会社を保険にしたりしない
I'm not using the company
as a safety net!
フォン･ブラウンじゃなくちゃ
駄目なんだ！
I have to get
onto the Von Braun!
（チェンシン）そんなこと言って
受からなかったらどうするんだ
You may say that, but what if
you don't make it?
How will you
make a living?
どうやって暮らしてく？
タナベさんは
親にも説明しないといけないんだよ
You'll have to explain it to Tanabe-san
and your parents, right?
（ハチマキ）そんなにいろんなこと
考えれられっかよ
- I can't worry about
any of that!
（チェンシン）
それは子供の夢の追い方だろ
That's how children chase after their dreams!
But you and I are adults!
僕たちは大人なんだ！
上手に生きたいなら
夢なんて語んな！
If you want a secure life,
don't you dare talk about dreams!
（チェンシン）周りのことも
考えろって言ってるんだ
I'm just saying that you need to think
about the people around you!
送別会も出ないで
空間喪失症になったときも―
You didn't even go to
your farewell party!
When you had Spatial Loss Disorder, we did
you a favor and sent you that care package!
みんなで
お見舞いを送ってやったのに
送ってやった？
押しつけの友情なら要らねえよ！
"Did me a favor"? I don't need friendship
shoved down my throat, jack!
うっ…
（ハチマキ）俺は俺だけのために
フォン･ブラウンに乗る
I'm getting onto the Von Braun
for myself, nobody else.
人類とか会社とか仲間とか
いちいち何かを言い訳にすんな！
Don't use humanity, or the company, or friends,
or any of that crap as excuses!
ううっ…
You stay here and futz around
Earth orbit all you want.
（ハチマキ）お前は
地球の周りをはいずり回っていろ
木星には 俺が行く
Me, I'm going
to Jupiter.
1303番―
#1303, Hoshino Hachirota.
星野八郎太(はちろうた)
♪～
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪グッと水を飲み干し
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Tentative Steps
（ラビィ）はい～
Hi! Welcome! Welcome!
♪ようこそ ようこそ
The wonderful Debris Section,
the happy Debris Section,
♪すてきなデブリ課
愉快なデブリ課
...gives you a hearty,
thankful welcome!
♪熱烈御礼 大歓迎
Hi! Welcome! Welcome!
♪ようこそ ようこそ
♪すてきなデブリ課
愉快なデブリ課
The wonderful Debris Section,
the happy Debris Section,
...gives you a hearty,
thankful welcome!
♪熱烈御礼 大歓迎
♪すてきなデブリ課
愉快なデブリ課
The wonderful Debris Section,
the happy Debris Section,
♪熱烈御礼
...gives you a hearty,
thankful welcome!
（課長･ラビィ）
♪大歓迎
（課長）あ痛っ…
（ラビィ）あれ？
Huh?